Inventory of the Minnie A. Hill Papers 1865-1869
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Minnie A. Hill Papers 1865-1869 1865-1869
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2008.48
0.30
This collection consists of letters from supervisors or sponsors to Minnie A. Hill, a northern female teacher, who was in Norfolk and then Petersburg, Virginia teaching at freedmen’s schools in the late 1860s.
Hill, Minnie A. arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 05/16/2008.
Biographical Note
Minnie A. Hill began her tenure at the National Freedman’s Relief Association in 1865, receiving her initial commission to serve as a teacher in Petersburg, Virginia. It appears she previously taught at a school in Norfolk, Virginia. In 1866, the Freedman’s Union Commission reappointed Hill to another one year term. In 1867, the Commission appointed Hill as principal of a school on Pocahontas Island in Petersburg, where she served until at least 1869. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Minnie A. Hill.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of letters from supervisors or sponsors to Minnie A. Hill, a northern female teacher, who was in Norfolk and then Petersburg, Virginia teaching at freedmen’s schools in the late 1860s.
Arrangement of Materials
Arranged chronologically.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Freedman's Union Commission (U.S.); National Freedman's Relief Association.
Genre/Form of Material:
Letters (correspondence)
Geographic Name:
Buffalo (N.Y.); New York (N.Y.)
Topical Term:
African Americans--Education--Virginia.; African Americans--Virginia--History--19th century.; Norfolk (Va.)--History--19th century.; Petersburg (Va.)--History--19th century.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- id72286 (Box 1)
  - C.A. Bloomer, Buffalo N.Y., to M.A. Hill, n.p., March 13, 1865; id29348 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - P.A. Balcom Jr., Buffalo N.Y., to Miss Hills, Norfolk Va., May 17, 1865; id29345 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - W.G. Hawkins, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, Norfolk Va., October 3, 1865; id29445 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - F.G. Shaw, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, Petersburg Va., October 7, 1865; id29454 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - W.G. Hawkins, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, Petersburg Va., February 8, 1866; id29460 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - C. Kennedy, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, n.p., September 22, 1866; id29461 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - F.G. Shaw, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, n.p, October 1, 1866; id29462 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - E.C. Estes, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, Petersburg Va., July 21, 1867; id29463 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - E.C. Estes, New York N.Y., July 24, 1867; id29464 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - W.G. Hawkins, “Rippen Hall” York County Va., to M.A. Hill, n.p., September 2, 1867; id29465 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - C. Kennedy, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, n.p., September 17, 1867; id29466 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - C. Kennedy, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, Petersburg Va., October 21, 1867; id29467 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - C. Kennedy, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, Petersburg Va., December 6, 1867; id29468 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - E.C. Estes, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, Petersburg Va., January 11, 1868; id29469 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - E.C. Estes, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, Petersburg Va., April, 1868; id29470 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - E.C. Estes, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, Petersburg Va., June 13, 1868; id29471 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - E.C. Estes, New York N.Y., to M.A. Hill, Petersburg, Va., July 3, 1868; id29472 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - J.W. Turner, Petersburg Va., to M.A. Hill, n.p., April 26, 1869; id29473 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - E.C. Estes, n.p., to M.A. Hill, n.p., undated; id29474 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - E.C. Estes, n.p., to M.A. Hill, n.p., undated; id29475 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - E.C. Estes, n.p., to M.A. Hill, n.p., undated; id29476 (Box 1, Folder 21)